<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Hegarty learning to code in ruby</title>
    <description>Documenting my path to learning the ruby language and ruby on rails from absolute beginner. </description>
    <link>http://jheg.co.uk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jheg.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 21:55:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://jheg.co.uk/jekyll/update/2014/06/28/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jheg.co.uk/jekyll/update/2014/06/28/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning ruby starts here</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago I decided that I wanted to learn a programming language and after much procrastination I ended up at the gotealeaf online bootcamp for learning ruby and ruby on rails. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll go into more detail on my background in a future post but first of all I needed somewhere to write about my journey and although I have a little experience with wordpress I wanted something different, preferably written in ruby. I asked the question on the #ruby channel on irc and got a huge list of potential solutions. I liked the sound of jekyll as it seems to have decent documentation and its own channel on irc #jekyll. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of explaining things in the way I need things explaining I will try to document each step of what I have done in a really easy to follow format so hopefully anyone wishing to follow the same path may find my experience of use in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably change the style of this blog from the default template at some point when I want a break from ruby but to be honest I quite like its simplicity. I’ll also look to add some other functionality to it like a comments section soon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed I’ll click save and this will show on my new created blog page!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yay it worked!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 21:55:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://jheg.co.uk/jekyll/update/2014/06/28/finding-my-blogging-platform/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jheg.co.uk/jekyll/update/2014/06/28/finding-my-blogging-platform/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I came to choose ruby as the language to study</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Up until recently the only languages I’d been exposed to were html, css, and the tiniest bit of javascript and php. The latter two there are mainly as a result of surrounding myself with friends that code for a living by way of hangin out in irc (internet relay chat). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats actually a really important part of my journey - in fact the most important part. About five years ago I decided I wanted to learn how to make a website for my small business and from a very early stage I realised the importance of internet forums and chat rooms. It taught me that the developer community was in the most part, incredibly supportive of anyone looking to learn the craft of code. I’ve met some fantastic people people over the past few years online and now regard these people as true friends even though I’ve never met a single one of them. 8 of us started a web design forum about a year ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewebdesignforum.co.uk&quot;&gt;thewebdesignforum&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bootcamp learning&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 21:55:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://jheg.co.uk/beginning/2014/06/28/draft_post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jheg.co.uk/beginning/2014/06/28/draft_post/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
